漫威影業
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
最新連載海外影視劇下載
請登陸 www.YYeTs.com
僅供學習  禁止用于任何商業盈利行為
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
阿富汗  庫納爾省
翻譯     草草
校對     草草
時間軸    光速俠安斯
時間軸    龜速俠吉吉
后期     吉吉
這氣氛像是在送我上軍事法庭
I feel like you're driving me to a court-martial.
真是的  我做了什么啊
This is crazy. What did I do?
感覺像是你們會停下車  然后滅了我
I feel like you're going to pull over and snuff me.
怎么  你們不許說話嗎
What, you're not allowed to talk?
阿甘哥
Hey, Forrest!
我們可以說話的  先生
We can talk, sir.
好啊  那是對我有意見咯
I see. So it's personal?
不  你讓他們害怕
No, you intimidate them.
老天爺  你是個妹子
Good God, you're a woman.
我真是沒看出來
I honestly... I couldn't have called that.
我是覺得該道歉  但要的就是這個效果吧
I mean, I'd apologise, but isn't that what we're going for here?
-我要首先把你當成士兵  -我是空軍
- I thought of you as a soldier first. - I'm an airman.
你的骨骼結構可真不錯
You have, actually, excellent bone structure, there.
我現在眼睛都沒法從你身上移開了
I'm kind of having a hard time not looking at you now.
這樣奇怪嗎
Is that weird?
好啦  笑笑嘛  沒事的
Come on, it's okay, laugh.
-先生  我有個問題  -問吧
- Sir, I have a question to ask. - Yes, please.
您真跟去年《馬克西姆》男士雜志的
Is it true you went 12 for 12
12位封面女郎都搞過嗎
with last year's Maxim cover models?
這問題問得好  是  也不是
That is an excellent question. Yes and no.
三月女郎跟我有日程沖突
March and I had a scheduling conflict,
但幸好  圣誕刊的封面是雙胞胎
but fortunately, the Christmas cover was twins.
還有問題嗎
Anything else?
你這舉手是在開玩笑吧
You're kidding me with the hand up, right?
-我可以跟您合個影嗎  -非常可以
- Is it cool if I take a picture with you? - Yes. It's very cool.
好
All right.
可別給發到你的"我的空間"主頁上
I don't want to see this on your MySpace page.
拜托  別比黑幫手勢
Please, no gang signs.
開玩笑的  舉起來吧
No, throw it up. I'm kidding.
和平  我愛和平
Yeah, peace. I love peace.
要是和平了我就沒生意了
I'd be out of a job with peace.
快點啊  快按鍵拍照
Come on. Hurry up. Just click it.
別改設置
Don't change any settings.
-怎么回事  -左側遇敵
- What's going on? - Contact left!
什么情況
What have we got?
吉米  守住斯塔克
Jimmy, stay with Stark!
-趴下  -嗯
- Stay down! - Yeah.
該死
Son of a bitch!
-等等  給我把槍  -待在這兒
- Wait, wait, wait! Give me a gun! - Stay here!
斯塔克工業
鋼鐵俠
托尼·斯塔克
Tony Stark.
鋼鐵俠
托尼·斯塔克
Tony Stark.
拉斯維加斯  36小時前
遠見家  天才
Visionary. Genius.
拉斯維加斯  36小時前
美國愛國者
American patriot.
拉斯維加斯  36小時前
美國愛國者
American patriot.
甚至還年少時
Even from an early age,
傳奇武器開發者霍華德·斯塔克的兒子
the son of legendary weapons developer Howard Stark
就很快憑其杰出獨特的頭腦吸引了大眾目光
quickly stole the spotlight with his brilliant and unique mind.
四歲時  他搭建了第一塊電路板
At age four, he built his first circuit board.
六歲時  他搭建了第一臺引擎
At age six, his first engine.
有其父必有其子  六歲的托尼·斯塔克建造出他的首臺V8發動機
六歲時  他搭建了第一臺引擎
At age six, his first engine.
有其父必有其子  六歲的托尼·斯塔克建造出他的首臺V8發動機
17歲時  他便以最優成績從麻省理工學院畢業
And at 17, he graduated summa cum laude from MIT.
有其父必有其子  六歲的托尼·斯塔克建造出他的首臺V8發動機
17歲時  他便以最優成績從麻省理工學院畢業
And at 17, he graduated summa cum laude from MIT.
托尼·斯塔克  麻省理工學院的機器人神童
17歲時  他便以最優成績從麻省理工學院畢業
And at 17, he graduated summa cum laude from MIT.
托尼·斯塔克  麻省理工學院的機器人神童
之后  一位巨頭逝世
Then, the passing of a titan.
霍華德和瑪麗亞·斯塔克死于車禍  舉國為夫妻哀悼
之后  一位巨頭逝世
Then, the passing of a titan.
霍華德和瑪麗亞·斯塔克死于車禍  舉國為夫妻哀悼
霍華德·斯塔克終身的朋友和盟友
Howard Stark's lifelong friend and ally,
奧巴代亞·斯坦尼接手
Obadiah Stane, steps in
填補了傳奇創始人留下的空缺
to help fill the gap left by the legendary founder,
直到21歲的浪子回歸
until, at age 21, the prodigal son returns
新來者  托尼·斯塔克21歲掌權
直到21歲的浪子回歸
until, at age 21, the prodigal son returns
新來者  托尼·斯塔克21歲掌權
成為了斯塔克工業的新執行總裁
and is anointed the new CEO of Stark lndustries.
新來者  托尼·斯塔克21歲掌權
成為了斯塔克工業的新執行總裁
and is anointed the new CEO of Stark lndustries.
掌握了王國的鑰匙后
With the keys to the kingdom,
托尼將父親的遺產帶入了新的時代
Tony ushers in a new era for his father's legacy,
制造了更智能的武器
creating smarter weapons,
先進機器人  衛星瞄準
advanced robotics, satellite targeting.
托尼·斯塔克想拯救世界
先進機器人  衛星瞄準
advanced robotics, satellite targeting.
如今  托尼·斯塔克
Today, Tony Stark
托尼·斯塔克想拯救世界
已改變了武器行業的面目
has changed the face of the weapons industry
托尼·斯塔克想拯救世界
他確保了自由  并在全球
by ensuring freedom and protecting America
托尼·斯塔克想拯救世界
他確保了自由  并在全球
by ensuring freedom and protecting America
保護美國和其利益
and her interests around the globe.
作為與斯塔克工業的聯絡人
As liaison to Stark Industries,
我格外榮幸地能與一位真正的愛國者共事
I've had the unique privilege of serving with a real patriot.
他是我的朋友  也是我的好導師
He is my friend and he is my great mentor.
女士們先生們  我很榮幸能將今年的
Ladies and gentlemen, it is my honour to present
極點獎授予托尼·斯塔克先生
this year's Apogee Award to Mr Tony Stark.
托尼
Tony?
-謝謝  中校  -謝謝救場
- Thank you, Colonel. - Thanks for the save.
這太美了  謝謝  非常感謝大家
This is beautiful. Thank you. Thank you all very much.
這太棒了
This is wonderful.
我不是托尼·斯塔克
Well, l'm not Tony Stark.
但如果我是托尼
But if I were Tony,
我會告訴你們我感到多么榮幸
I would tell you how honoured I feel
以及接受如此高的榮譽
and what a joy it is to receive this very
是多么令人開心
prestigious award.
托尼  要知道
Tony, you know...
托尼最棒的地方  也是他最糟的地方
The best thing about Tony is also the worst thing.
他總在工作
He's always working.
瞧啊
Work it!
這多棒
Come on!
-我們該一直待到早上  -你真是難以置信
- We should just stay till the morning. - You are unbelievable.
糟糕  是他們叫你來的嗎
Oh, no! Did they rope you into this?
沒誰叫我做什么
Nobody roped me into anything!
-對不起  -但他們跟我說
- I'm so sorry. - But they told me that
如果由我來給你頒獎  你會倍感榮幸
if I presented you with an award, you'd be deeply honoured.
那是當然  是你頒獎  多棒
Of course I'd be deeply honoured. And it's you, that's great.
-我們什么時候頒  -在這兒呢
- So when do we do it? - It's right here.
-再來一輪  -給
- One more round. - Here you go.
在這兒啊  好輕松
There it is. That was easy.
-真對不起  -沒關系
- I'm so sorry. - Yeah, it's okay.
看啊  這多特別
Would you look at that? That's something else.
這玩意我還沒拿過呢
I don't have any of those floating around.
我們試試運氣吧
We're gonna let it ride!
給我點運氣吧  祝福一下
Give me a hand, will you? Give me a little something-something.
好  你也來
Okay, you, too.
-我不吹別人的骰子  -來嘛  蜜熊
- I don't blow on a man's dice. - Come on, honey bear.
好嘞  羅德中校扔骰子咯
There it is. Lieutenant Colonel Rhodes rolls! And...
兩點  好了
Two craps. Line away.
-就這樣了  -這還不算最糟的
- That's what happens. - Worse things have happened.
不會有事的  請幫我把籌碼整理好
I think we're gonna be fine. Colour me up, will you?
-我要走了  -好
- This is where I exit. - All right.
明天  別遲到了
Tomorrow, don't be late.
-嗯  沒問題  -我說真的
- Yeah, you can count on it. - I'm serious!
我知道
I know, I know.
凱撒的東西給凱撒吧  給
Render unto Caesar that which is Caesar's. There you go.
斯塔克先生  等等  斯塔克先生
Mr Stark! Excuse me, Mr Stark!
克莉絲汀·艾凡哈特  《名利場》雜志的
Christine Everhart, Vanity Fair magazine.
可以問您幾個問題嗎
Can I ask you a couple of questions?
-她很美  -是嗎
- She's cute. - She's all right?
-當然  問吧  -行嗎
- Yeah. Okay, go. - It's okay?
您被稱為當代達·芬奇
You've been called the da Vinci of our time.
您對此有何看法
What do you say to that?
荒唐  我又不會畫畫
Absolutely ridiculous. I don't paint.
那您怎么看待你的其他外號
And what do you say to your other nickname?
"死亡商人"
"The Merchant of Death"?
這不算壞
That's not bad.
我猜猜  伯克利畢業的
Let me guess. Berkeley?
其實是布朗大學
Brown, actually.
布朗大學小姐
Well, Ms Brown,
這是個不完美的世界  但我們只有這個世界
it's an imperfect world, but it's the only one we've got.
我向你保證
I guarantee you,
如果哪天再不需要武器來維護和平了
the day weapons are no longer needed to keep the peace,
我會開始為嬰兒醫院制造建材的
I'll start making bricks and beams for baby hospitals.
這段話常練嗎
Rehearse that much?
每晚睡覺前都會對著鏡子說
Every night in front of the mirror before bedtime.
-看出來了  -我想讓你親眼見識一下
- I can see that. - I'd like to show you first-hand.
我只想要個嚴肅的答案
All I want is a serious answer.
好吧  說嚴肅的  我老爸有個理論
Okay, here's serious. My old man had a philosophy,
"和平就是比對方的棍子大"
"Peace means having a bigger stick than the other guy."
賣棍子的人說這話真討巧
That's a great line coming from the guy selling the sticks.
我父親幫忙打敗了納粹
My father helped defeat the Nazis.
他還參與了曼哈頓計劃[原子彈]
He worked on the Manhattan Project.
很多人  包括你布朗大學的教授們
A lot of people, including your professors at Brown,
都會認為這叫英雄
would call that being a hero.
也會有很多人稱之為戰爭牟利
And a lot of people would also call that war profiteering.
告訴我  你打算報道我們靠推動醫療科技
Tell me, do you plan to report on the millions we've saved
和改善農業技術
by advancing medical technology
而讓千百萬人延續壽命  免受饑荒的事嗎
or kept from starvation with our intelli-crops?
所有那些突破
All those breakthroughs,
都是由軍工提供的資金  親愛的
military funding, honey.
你這輩子失眠過嗎
You ever lose an hour of sleep your whole life?
我愿意跟你失眠幾小時
I'd be prepared to lose a few with you.
早上好  現在是早7點
Good morning. It's 7:00 a.m.
馬里布氣溫為22度  少云
The weather in Malibu is 72 degrees with scattered clouds.
沖浪條件不錯  海浪到腰和肩之間
The surf conditions are fair with waist-to-shoulder high lines.
高潮時間為上午10:52
High tide will be at 10:52 a.m.
加州  馬里布
托尼
Tony?
Hey, Tony?
你無權進入這個區域
You are not authorised to access this area.
-天吶  -那是賈維斯  他是房子的管家
- Jesus. - That's Jarvis. He runs the house.
這是你的衣服  干洗熨燙過了
I've got your clothes here. They've been dry-cleaned and pressed,
外面有輛車在等著你
and there's a car waiting for you outside
會帶你去任何你指定的地方
that will take you anywhere you'd like to go.
-你一定是著名的派珀·波茨  -是的
- You must be the famous Pepper Potts. - Indeed I am.
都這么多年了
After all these years,
托尼還讓你替他拿干洗衣物
Tony still has you picking up the dry-cleaning.
我做任何斯塔克先生要我做的事
I do anything and everything that Mr Stark requires,
偶爾也包括倒垃圾
including, occasionally, taking out the trash.
沒有別的事了吧
Will that be all?
擴展視圖
Give me an exploded view.
3號氣缸的氣壓似乎過低了
The compression in cylinder three appears to be low.
記錄一下
Log that.
-我這就再試一次  -請別把我的音樂關小
- I'm gonna try again, right now. - Please don't turn down my music.
我再通知你
I'll keep you posted.
你現在應該在去往地球另一邊的路上了
You are supposed to be halfway around the world right now.
-她接受得如何  -非常好
- How'd she take it? - Like a champ.
你為什么急著趕我走
Why are you trying to hustle me out of here?
你的航班應該是一個半小時前離開的
Your flight was scheduled to leave an hour and a half ago.
有意思  我以為考慮到那是我的飛機
That's funny, I thought with it being my plane and all,
它會等我到了再出發呢
that it would just wait for me to get there.
托尼  我有幾件事要跟你商量
Tony, I need to speak to you about a couple things
然后我就要送你出門了
before I get you out of the door.
如果你還沒到  飛機就飛了
Doesn't it kind of defeat the whole purpose
那有自己的飛機
of having your own plane
不就沒意義了嗎
if it departs before you arrive?
拉里來電
Larry called.
他為杰克遜·波洛克畫找到了新買家
He's got another buyer for the Jackson Pollock in the wings.
你還想不想要它
Do you want it? Yes or no.
那是他的"春"期代表作嗎
Is it a good representation of his spring period?
不是  斯普林斯是他曾生活工作過的
No. The Springs was actually the neighbourhood in East Hampton
一個東漢普頓社區
where he lived and worked,
-并不是春天的"春"  -是嗎
- not "spring" like the season. - So?
我覺得還可以  而且定價過高了
I think it's a fair example. I think it's incredibly overpriced.
我要  買  存起來
I need it. Buy it. Store it.
好  麻省理工學院畢業典禮講話
Okay. The MIT commencement speech...
6月的事  拜托
Is in June. Please,
別拿還沒影的事來嘮叨我
don't harangue me about stuff that's way, way, down...
他們在嘮叨我  我就答應了
They're haranguing me, so I'm gonna say yes.
反彈或吸收
Deflect it and absorb it.
-別傳遞給我  -你上機前
- Don't transmit it back to me. - I need you to sign this
-我需要你給這個簽字  -你干嗎非要趕我走
- before you get on the plane. - What are you trying to get rid of me for?
你有安排嗎
What, you got plans?
-事實上  真有  -我不喜歡你有安排
- As a matter of fact, I do. - I don't like it when you have plans.
我生日這天是可以有安排的
I'm allowed to have plans on my birthday.
-今天是你生日嗎  -嗯
- It's your birthday? - Yes.
我知道的  這就到了嗎
I knew that. Already?
是的  多奇怪啊  跟去年是同一天
Yeah. Isn't that strange? It's the same day as last year.
-拿我的錢給自己買點好東西吧  -買了
- Get yourself something nice from me. - I already did.
-怎么樣  -可好了
- And? - It was very nice.
-嗯  -很有品味  謝謝  斯塔克先生
- Yeah. - Very tasteful. Thank you, Mr Stark.
不客氣  波茨小姐
You're welcome, Miss Potts.
好了
Okay.
你挺厲害  我剛剛以為甩掉你了
You're good. I thought I lost you back there.
是這樣  先生
You did, sir.
我不得不抄穆赫蘭道的捷徑
I had to cut across Mulholland.
被我甩掉了吧
I got you. I got you.
你什么毛病
What's wrong with you?
-怎么了  -三小時
- What? - Three hours.
忙著接受《名利場》的采訪呢
I got caught doing a piece for Vanity Fair.
三小時  你讓我在這兒站了三小時
For three hours. For three hours you got me standing here.
現在等你了  走吧  快來
Waiting on you now. Let's go. Come on.
起飛  開始吧
Wheels up! Rock and roll!
-你看什么呢  鴨嘴獸  -沒事
- What you reading, platypus? - Nothing.
得了  酸糖娃  別生氣嘛
Come on, sour patch. Don't be mad.
我說了  我沒生氣  我不在乎  好嗎
I told you, I'm not mad. I'm indifferent, okay?
-我都道歉了  -早上好  斯塔克先生
- I said I was sorry. - Good morning, Mr Stark.
你不用向我道歉
You don't need to apologise to me.
-我是你的哥們  -我都跟他道歉了  但他
- I'm your man. - I told him I was sorry, but he...
-我現在就是不在乎了  -熱毛巾要嗎
- I'm just indifferent right now. - Hot towel?
你不尊重自己  所以我知道你不尊重我
You don't respect yourself, so I know you don't respect me.
-我尊重你  -我就是你的保姆
- I respect you. - I'm just your babysitter.
如果你需要換尿布了  謝謝
So, when you need your diaper changed... Thank you.
就告訴我  我去給你拿奶瓶  好嗎
Let me know and I'll get you a bottle, okay?
加熱下清酒  好嗎
Heat up the sake, will you?
-多謝提醒我  -我不是說
- Thanks for reminding me. - No, I'm not talking...
我們不喝酒  我們在工作
We're not drinking. We're working right now.
-吃生魚片一定要配清酒  -你根本就是
- You can't have sashimi without sake. - You are constitutionally
做不到負責任
incapable of being responsible.
不喝酒才不負責
It would be irresponsible not to drink.
不過是一杯睡前酒
I'm just talking about a nightcap.
熱清酒
Hot sake?
好  來兩杯  謝謝
Yes, two, please.
不  我不喝  我不要
No. I'm not drinking. I don't want any.
我就這意思
That's what I'm talking about.
我早上起床  穿上軍服
When I get up in the morning and I'm putting on my uniform,
知道我認得什么嗎
you know what I recognise?
我在鏡子里能看到
I see in that mirror that
每一個穿著這軍服的人都會照應我
every person that's got this uniform on got my back!
知道嗎  我跟你不一樣  我不適合
Hey, you know what? I'm not like you. I'm not cut out...
不  你不非得像我一樣
No, no. You don't have to be like me!
但你遠不止現在的你自己
But you're more than what you are.
抱歉  我現在有點無法集中精神
Can you excuse me if I'm a bit distracted here?
不  你現在不能不集中精神  聽我說
No! You can't be distracted right now! Listen to me!
阿富汗  巴格蘭空軍基地
將軍
General.
歡迎  斯塔克先生
Welcome, Mr Stark.
我們很期待您的武器展示
We look forward to your weapons presentation.
謝謝
Thanks.
被恐懼和被尊敬  哪個更好
Is it better to be feared or respected?
要我說  兩個都要算過分嗎
I say, is it too much to ask for both?
因此  我謙卑地獻上斯塔克工業
With that in mind, I humbly present the crown jewel
自由系列的旗艦產品
of Stark Industries' Freedom Line.
這是第一個融入了
It's the first missile system
我們的專利沖擊科技的導彈系統
to incorporate our proprietary repulsor technology.
人說最好的武器是不需要使用的武器
They say the best weapon is one you never have to fire.
我尊重地表示不同意
I respectfully disagree.
我更喜歡你只需要使用一次的武器
I prefer the weapon you only have to fire once.
我老爸就這么做  美國就這么做
That's how Dad did it. That's how America does it.
而且到目前一直挺成功
And it's worked out pretty well so far.
找個借口
Find an excuse
發射一次這玩意  我親自擔保
to let one of these off the chain, and I personally guarantee you
壞蛋再也不會想從洞里爬出來了
the bad guys won't even want to come out of their caves.
供您參考  耶利哥
For your consideration, the Jericho.
每筆超過五億的交易
I'll be throwing one of these in
我送一個這個
with every purchase of 500 million or more.
敬和平
To peace!
-托尼  -奧比  你怎么起來了
- Tony. - Obie, what are you doing up?
不清楚情況我睡不著  展示得怎么樣
I couldn't sleep till I found out how it went. How'd it go?
很好  看來圣誕節要提前了
It went great. Looks like it's gonna be an early Christmas.
好樣的  伙計  明天見了
Way to go, my boy! I'll see you tomorrow, yeah?
你怎么沒穿我送你的睡衣
Why aren't you wearing those pyjamas I got you?
晚安  托尼
Good night, Tony.
-托尼  -抱歉  這輛車是"歡樂馬"
- Hey, Tony. - I'm sorry, this is the "Fun-vee."
"悍無聊馬"在后面
The "Hum-drum-vee" Is back there.
-好樣的  -基地見
- Nice job. - See you back at base.
我勸你別那么做
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
你對我做了什么
What the hell did you do to me?
我做了什么
What I did?
我做的事是救你命
What I did is to save your life.
我已經盡力移除了很多彈片  但還剩不少
I removed all the shrapnel I could, but there's a lot left,
而且它們都在往你的房隔去
and it's headed into your atrial septum.
想看看嗎
Here, want to see?
我留了紀念品  看看吧
I have a souvenir. Take a look.
我在我的村子里見過不少這樣的傷
I've seen many wounds like that in my village.
我們稱他們為將死行尸
We call them the walking dead
因為大概要一周
because it takes about a week
彈片才會進入重要器官
for the barbs to reach the vital organs.
-這是什么  -那是塊電磁鐵
- What is this? - That is an electromagnet,
連在了汽車電池上
hooked up to a car battery,
它在阻止彈片進入你的心臟
and it's keeping the shrapnel from entering your heart.
沒錯  笑笑
That's right. Smile.
我們見過一次  在伯爾尼的一場科技大會上
We met once, you know, at a technical conference in Bern.
-我不記得了  -當然了
- I don't remember. - No, you wouldn't.
如果我喝得那么醉  肯定站都站不直
If I had been that drunk, I wouldn't have been able to stand,
更別說就集成電路發表講話了
much less give a lecture on integrated circuits.
我們在哪
Where are we?
快起來  起來
Come on, stand up. Stand up!
學我的樣子做
Just do as I do.
把手舉起來
Come on, put your hands up.
那是我的槍  他們怎么弄到的
Those are my guns. How did they get my guns?
你聽懂了沒  學我的樣子做
Do you understand me? Do as I do.
他說"歡迎  托尼·斯塔克  美國歷史上
He says, "Welcome, Tony Stark, the most famous mass murderer
最著名的大屠殺犯"
in the history of America."
他很榮幸
He is honoured.
他要你給他建導彈
He wants you to build the missile.
你展示的那個耶利哥導彈
The Jericho missile that you demonstrated.
這個
This one.
我拒絕
I refuse.
托尼
Tony!
斯塔克工業
他問你覺得怎么樣
He wants to know what you think.
我覺得你有好多我的武器
I think you got a lot of my weapons.
他說他們有你需要
He says they have everything
拿來建造耶利哥的一切
you need to build the Jericho missile.
他要你列出材料清單
He wants you to make the list of materials.
他說要你立刻開始動手
He says for you to start working immediately,
你做好了  他就放了你
and when you're done, he will set you free.
-不  他不會的  -是啊
- No, he won't. - No, he won't.
他們肯定在找你  斯塔克
I'm sure they're looking for you, Stark.
但在這些山里  他們是找不到你的
But they will never find you in these mountains.
你剛剛看到一切
Look, what you just saw,
那就是你的遺產  斯塔克
that is your legacy, Stark.
你一生的心血  落在那些殺人犯手里
Your life's work, in the hands of those murderers.
你想這樣死去嗎
Is that how you want to go out?
這就是偉大的托尼·斯塔克的
Is this the last act of defiance
最后反抗嗎
of the great Tony Stark?
還是說你要想想辦法
Or are you going to do something about it?
我何必還要做點什么
Why should I do anything?
他們無論如何都會殺了你  殺了我
They're going to kill me, you, either way.
就算不  我大概也活不過一周
And if they don't, I'll probably be dead in a week.
那么
Well, then,
這一周就對你至關重要了吧
this is a very important week for you, isn't it?
如果這里要做我的工作站
If this is going to be my work station,
我要燈火通明  這個豎好
I want it well-lit. I want these up.
我需要焊接工具  乙炔和丙烷的都行
I need welding gear. I don't care if it's acetylene or propane.
我需要焊接工作臺
I need a soldering station.
頭盔  護目鏡
I need helmets. I'm gonna need goggles.
我還要熔煉杯  兩組精密工具
I would like a smelting cup. I need two sets of precision tools.
斯塔克工業
-你說多少種語言  -好多種
- How many languages do you speak? - A lot.
但看來在這里還是不夠用
But apparently, not enough for this place.
他們說阿拉伯語  烏爾都語
They speak Arabic, Urdu,
達里語  帕施圖語
dari, Pashto,
蒙古語  波斯語  俄語
Mongolian, Farsi, Russian.
他們是什么人
Who are these people?
他們是你的忠實顧客  先生
They are your loyal customers, sir.
他們自稱"十戒組織"
They call themselves the Ten Rings.
如果你告訴我你的計劃
You know, we might be more productive
我們的動作可能會更快
if you include me in the planning process.
好吧  我們不需要這個
Okay, we don't need this.
那是什么
What is that?
鈀  0.15克
That's palladium, 0.15 grammes.
我們需要至少1.6
We need at least 1.6,
你去把另外11個拆了吧
so why don't you go break down the other 11?
他在干什么
What's he doing?
干活兒
Working.
小心  我們只有一次機會
Careful. Careful, we only get one shot at this.
放心  我手很穩
Relax. I have steady hands.
要不你怎么會還活著
Why do you think you're still alive?
-怎么稱呼你  -我叫殷森
- What do I call you? - My name is Yinsen.
殷森  認識你很高興
Yinsen. Nice to meet you.
我也很高興認識你
Nice to meet you, too.
那看上去不像耶利哥導彈
That doesn't look like a Jericho missile.
因為那是個迷你方舟反應堆
That's because it's a miniaturised arc reactor.
我家里有個大的給我的工廠供電
I got a big one powering my factory at home.
這應該足以阻止彈片進入我的心臟
It should keep the shrapnel out of my heart.
但它能產生什么
But what could it generate?
如果我沒算錯  我通常不會算錯
If my math is right, and it always is,
每秒能產生3千兆焦耳
three gigajoules per second.
那足以讓你的心跳50輩子
That could run your heart for 50 lifetimes.
或者讓什么大玩意跑15分鐘
Or something big for 15 minutes.
-這是我們逃離的方法  -是什么
- This is our ticket out of here. - What is it?
攤平了看
Flatten them out and look.
厲害
Impressive.
很好
Good.
下得好
Good roll. Good roll.
你還沒跟我說你是哪里人
You still haven't told me where you're from.
我來自一個叫科米拉的小鎮
I'm from a small town called Gulmira.
-那里其實很不錯  -有家人嗎
- It's actually a nice place. - Got a family?
有  等我離開這里  就能見到他們
Yes, and I will see them when I leave here.
你呢  斯塔克
And you, Stark?
-沒有  -沒有嗎
- No. - No?
你是個擁有一切的人
So you're a man who has everything
卻一無所有
and nothing.
看上去完全不像照片上的東西
It doesn't look anything like the picture.
或許是改裝過了
Maybe it's been modified.
尾翼不對
The tail is wrong.
就是倒過來了
It's just backwards.
放松
Relax.
弓和箭
The bow and arrow
曾是武器科技的巔峰
once was the pinnacle of weapons technology.
讓偉大的成吉思汗
It allowed the great Genghis Khan
一統從太平洋到烏克蘭之間的土地
to rule from the Pacific to the Ukraine.
他的帝國是亞歷山大大帝的兩倍
An empire twice the size of Alexander the Great
是羅馬帝國的四倍
and four times the size of the Roman Empire.
但今天
But today,
有最新的斯塔克工業武器的人
whoever holds the latest Stark weapons
就能統治這些土地
rules these lands.
很快
And soon,
就要輪到我了
it will be my turn.
你為什么讓我失望了
Why have you failed me?
我們在工作
We're working.
非常努力
Diligently.
我留了你一命
I let you live.
你就如此回報我嗎
This is how you repay me?
工作復雜
It's very complex.
他已經很盡力了
He's trying very hard.
讓他跪下
On his knees.
你當我傻嗎
You think I'm a fool?
我會問出真相的
I'll get the truth.
我們都在工作
We're both working.
張開嘴
Open your mouth.
他要什么
What does he want?
你當我傻嗎
You think I'm a fool?
究竟怎么回事
What's going on?
告訴我實話
Tell me the truth.
他在給你做耶利哥
He's building your Jericho.
你要什么  完成日期嗎
What do you want? A delivery date?
我需要他
I need him.
好助手
Good assistant.
明天把我的導彈組裝好
You have till tomorrow to assemble my missile.
行嗎  你能動嗎
Okay? Can you move?
好  再說一遍
Okay, say it again.
正前方41步
41 steps straight ahead.
出門16步右轉
Then 16 steps, that's from the door, fork right,
走33步  再右轉
33 steps, turn right.
斯塔克呢
Where is Stark?
他剛剛還在的
He was here a moment ago.
去找他
Go look for him.
殷森  殷森  斯塔克
Yinsen! Yinsen! Stark!
說話  對他說句話
Say something. Say something back to him.
他在說匈牙利語
He's speaking Hungarian.
-我不會  -那就說匈牙利語
- I don't... - Then speak Hungarian.
-好吧  我會...  -你會什么
- Okay. I know. - What do you know?
-怎么樣  -天吶
- How'd that work? - Oh, my goodness.
-倒是挺成功  -我就這樣
- It worked all right. - That's what I do.
-我把這個弄完  -去啟動動力程序
- Let me finish this. - Initialise the power sequence.
好
Okay.
-快  -你說
- Now! - Tell me. Tell me.
F11  看到進度條告訴我
Function 11 . Tell me when you see a progress bar.
-應該有了  -有了
- It should be up right now. - Yes.
跟我說  看到了嗎
Talk to me. Tell me when you see it.
-有了  -CTRL加I
- I have it. - Press Control "I".
-I  好  -I  回車
- "I." Got it. - "I." "Enter." "I" and "Enter."
過來  給我扣好
Come over here and button me up.
好了
Okay. All right.
六角螺栓  隔一個鎖一個
Every other hex bolt.
-他們來了  -很不妙  快完成
- They're coming! - Nothing pretty, just get it done.
-快完成  -他們來了
- Just get it done. - They're coming.
確認關卡都沒人了
Make sure the checkpoints are clear
再跟著我出去
before you follow me out, okay?
我們還需要時間
We need more time.
-我去給你爭取點時間  -按計劃來
- I'm gonna go buy you some time. - Stick to the plan!
按計劃來
Stick to the plan!
殷森
Yinsen!
-殷森  -小心
- Yinsen! - Watch out!
斯塔克
Stark.
快點  我們得走了
Come on. We got to go.
動一動啊  我們說好的  按計劃來
Move for me, come on. We got a plan. We're gonna stick to it.
我的計劃本就是如此  斯塔克
This was always the plan, Stark.
你還得去見家人呢  起來吧
Come on, you're gonna go see your family. Get up.
我的家人都死了
My family is dead.
我要去見他們了  斯塔克
I'm going to see them now, Stark.
沒事的
It's okay.
我想要這樣的
I want this. I want this.
謝謝你救我
Thank you for saving me.
別浪費  別浪費你的人生
Don't waste it. Don't waste your life.
該我了
My turn.
不賴了
Not bad.
"歡樂馬"怎么樣
How was the "Fun-vee"?
下次  你跟我一車  好嗎
Next time, you ride with me, okay?
小心  看著腳下
Watch it, coming up here.
開玩笑嗎  叫他們走開
Are you kidding me with this? Get rid of them.
你的眼睛紅了  為失蹤已久的老板落淚了嗎
Your eyes are red. A few tears for your long-lost boss?
是喜悅的眼淚  我討厭找工作
Tears of joy. I hate job hunting.
嗯  假期結束了
Yeah, vacation's over.
去哪  先生
Where to, sir?
-去醫院  -不
- Take us to the hospital. - No.
謝謝  哈皮  什么叫不  托尼
Please, Happy. No? Tony,
-你得去醫院  -不就是不
- you have to go to the hospital. - No is a complete answer.
-得讓醫生給你看看  -我不非得做什么
- The doctor has to look at you. - I don't have to do anything.
我被囚三個月了
I've been in captivity for three months.
我有兩件想做的事
There are two things I want to do.
我要一個美國奶酪漢堡
I want an American cheeseburger,
-還有一件...  -夠了
- and the other... - That's enough of that.
不是你想的那件
...is not what you think.
我要你馬上召開記者招待會
I want you to call for a press conference now.
-召開記者招待會  -是的
- Call for a press conference? - Yeah.
-為什么啊  -霍根  開車
- What on earth for? - Hogan, drive.
先去找漢堡
Cheeseburger first.
看啊
Look at this!
托尼
Tony.
-我們本想去醫院見你的  -我沒事
- We were going to meet at the hospital. - No, I'm fine.
看看你
Look at you!
-你非得買個漢堡  -拜托
- You had to have a burger, yeah? - Well, come on.
-給我買了嗎  -只剩一個了  我很想吃
- You get me one of those? - There's only one left. I need it.
看看誰來了  好啊
Hey, look who's here! Yeah!
-波茨小姐  -是
- Miss Potts? - Yes.
能跟你說句話嗎
Can I speak to you for a moment?
我不參加問答的
I'm not part of the press conference,
但記者招待會馬上就開始
but it's about to begin right now.
我不是記者
I'm not a reporter.
我是菲爾·科爾森特工
I'm Agent Phil Coulson,
我隸屬國土戰略防御攻擊
with the Strategic Homeland Intervention, Enforcement
與后勤保障局
and Logistics Division.
-好拗口  -是啊  我們還在改進
- That's quite a mouthful. - I know. We're working on it.
國防部  聯調局和中情局
You know, we've been approached already
都已經找過我們了
by the DOD, the FBI, the CIA...
我們是獨立部門  目標更明確專一
We're a separate division with a more specific focus.
我們需要詢問斯塔克先生
We need to debrief Mr Stark
關于他逃脫的具體情況
about the circumstances of his escape.
-我會加到日程里的  好嗎  -謝謝
- I'll put something in the book, shall I? - Thank you.
大家可以坐下嗎
Hey, would it be all right if everyone sat down?
你們都坐下吧
Why don't you just sit down?
這樣你們都能看到我  我也能...
That way you can see me, and I can...
這樣不那么正式
A little less formal and...
-怎么變成嬉皮士聚會了  -別問我
- What's up with the love-in? - Don't look at me.
我不知道他是想干什么
I don't know what he's up to.
-見到你真好  -我也是
- Good to see you. - Good to see you.
我沒能跟爸爸說再見
I never got to say goodbye to Dad.
我沒能跟我父親說再見
I never got to say goodbye to my father.
我有些問題想問他
There's questions that I would have asked him.
我想問他對公司的作為怎么看
I would have asked him how he felt about what this company did.
他是否有過掙扎  有過懷疑
If he was conflicted, if he ever had doubts.
或許他就完全是
Or maybe he was every inch
新聞紀錄片里的那個男人
the man we all remember from the newsreels.
我看到了年輕的美國人被殺
I saw young Americans killed
殺害他們的正是我為了維護他們而制造的武器
by the very weapons I created to defend them and protect them.
我還看到
And I saw that I
我已經成為了
had become part of a system
不愿負擔責任的系統的一員
that is comfortable with zero accountability.
-斯塔克先生  -本
- Mr Stark! - Hey, Ben.
你在那里經歷了什么
What happened over there?
我開了眼界  我意識到我可以為
I had my eyes opened. I came to realise that I have more
這世界做更多  而不只是制造爆炸
to offer this world than just making things that blow up.
因此  即刻生效  我要關閉
And that is why, effective immediately, I am shutting down
斯塔克國際公司的武器生產部
the weapons manufacturing division of Stark lnternational
直到
until such a time
我決定好公司的未來
as I can decide what the future of the company will be.
-大家這下不愁  -決定好它的走向
- I think we're gonna be... -  What direction it should take,
-賣不出報紙了  -我能接受的
- selling a lot of newspapers. - one that l'm comfortable with
并且與國家最高利益
and is consistent with the highest good
一致的走向
for this country, as well.
我們應該記住的
What we should take away from this
是托尼回來了
is that Tony's back!
而且非常健康
And he's healthier than ever.
我們將進行內部探討
We're going to have a little internal discussion
隨后向大家通報
and we'll get back to you with the follow-up.
-他人呢  -在里面
- Where is he? - He's inside.
那...挺順利嘛
Well, that... That went well.
我是在腦后放了個靶子嗎
Did I just paint a target on the back of my head?
你的腦袋  那我的腦袋呢
Your head? What about my head?
你覺得明天股價
What do you think the over-under on the stock
會跌到什么程度
drop is gonna be tomorrow?
-樂觀估計  40點  -至少
- Optimistically, 40 points. - At minimum.
是啊
Yep.
托尼  我們是武器制造商
Tony, we're a weapons manufacturer.
奧比  我不希望我們將來只留下殺傷數字
Obie, I just don't want a body count to be our only legacy.
這是我們的工作
That's what we do.
我們是鐵商  我們制造武器
We're iron mongers. We make weapons.
大樓上是我的名字
It's my name on the side of the building.
我們的工作讓世界不會陷入混亂
And what we do keeps the world from falling into chaos.
我看到的可不是這樣
Not based on what I saw.
我們做得不夠好
We're not doing a good enough job.
我們可以做得更好  我們要做別的
We can do better. We're gonna do something else.
什么別的  你要我們做奶瓶嗎
Like what? You want us to make baby bottles?
我認為我們該重新考慮方舟反應堆科技
I think we should take another look into arc reactor technology.
得了  方舟反應堆就是個噱頭
Come on. The arc reactor, that's a publicity stunt!
托尼  拜托
Tony, come on.
我們建這個是為了堵嬉皮士的嘴
We built that thing to shut the hippies up!
-成功了  -是啊  作為科學項目
- It works. - Yeah, as a science project.
方舟反應堆的效益性根本不好
The arc was never cost effective.
我們建造之前就知道了
We knew that before we built it.
方舟反應堆科技是個死胡同  是吧
Arc reactor technology, that's a dead end, right?
或許吧
Maybe.
是吧  我們在這方面多久沒有突破了
Am I right? We haven't had a breakthrough in that in what?
-30年嗎  -據說是的
- Thirty years. - That's what they say.
你的撲克臉能更糟點嗎  告訴我  誰說的
Could you have a lousier poker face? Just tell me, who told you?
-別管了  給我看  -羅德還是派珀
- Never mind who told me. Show me. - It's Rhodey or Pepper.
-我要看  -好吧  是羅德
- I want to see it. - Okay, Rhodey.
-好吧  -行嗎
- Okay. - Okay?
成功了
It works.
聽我說  托尼  我們是一隊的  懂嗎
Listen to me, Tony. We're a team. Do you understand?
只要我們合力  沒什么是做不到的
There's nothing we can't do if we stick together,
就像當年我和你父親
like your father and I.
抱歉我沒提前跟你商量
I'm sorry I didn't give you a heads-up, okay?
-但如果我說了  -托尼
- But if I had... - Tony.
托尼  別再干這種脫口而出的事了
Tony, no more of this "ready, fire, aim" business.
-明白嗎  -那是老爸常說的話
- You understand me? - That was Dad's line.
你得讓我來處理
You gotta let me handle this.
我們現在得玩另一套把戲了
We're gonna have to play a whole different kind of ball now.
我們要承受很大壓力
We're going to have to take a lot of heat.
我要你保證  你會低調些
I want you to promise me that you're gonna lay low.
斯塔克工業
Stark lndustries!
我給你推薦條路  準備好了嗎
I've got one recommendation! Ready? Ready?
賣賣賣
Sell, sell, sell!
棄船
Abandon ship!
興登堡飛艇的事記得嗎
Does the Hindenburg ring any bells?
我給大家看看
Let me show you
新斯塔克工業的商業計劃
the new Stark lndustries business plan!
這就是一家不造武器的武器公司
Look, that's a weapons company that doesn't make weapons!
派珀  你的手有多大
Pepper. How big are your hands?
-什么  -你的手有多大
- What? - How big are your hands?
-我不懂這...  -下來  我需要你
- I don't understand why... - Get down here. I need you.
伸出來  給我看看你的手
Let's see them. Show me your hands.
給我看看
Let's see them.
好小  好精巧
They are small. Very petite, indeed.
我需要你幫個忙
I just need your help for a sec.
天吶  那就是維系你生命的東西嗎
Oh, my God, is that the thing that's keeping you alive?
之前是  現在是古董了
It was. It is now an antique.
這個將在未來一段時間內維系我的生命
This is what will be keeping me alive for the foreseeable future.
我要換升級版的
I'm swapping it up for an upgraded unit,
現在遭遇了點障礙
and I just ran into a little speed bump.
障礙  什么意思
Speed bump, what does that mean?
沒事  就是個小問題
It's nothing. It's just a little snag.
這個裝置下面有條暴露的電線
There's an exposed wire under this device.
接觸到了槽壁
And it's contacting the socket wall
造成了短路
and causing a little bit of a short.
沒事的
It's fine.
-你要我做什么  -放在那邊桌上
- What do you want me to do? - Put that on the table over there.
-那個沒用了  -天吶
- That is irrelevant. - Oh, my God!
你伸手進去
I want you to reach in,
輕輕地把電線拉出來
and you're just gonna gently lift the wire out.
-安全嗎  -應該沒事
- Is it safe? - Yeah, it should be fine.
就像手術游戲  別讓電線
It's like Operation. You just don't let it
碰到槽壁就行  否則就會發出嗶聲
touch the socket wall or it goes "beep."
什么"手術游戲"
What do you mean, "Operation"?
就是個游戲  算了
It's just a game, never mind.
-輕輕地把電線拉出來  -好
- Just gently lift the wire. - Okay.
好嗎  很好
Okay? Great.
我覺得我做這個不夠格
You know, I don't think that I'm qualified to do this.
你可以的  你是我認識的最夠格
No, you're fine. You're the most capable, qualified,
最值得信賴的人  你會做得很棒的
trustworthy person I've ever met. You're gonna do great.
這個要求太過分了嗎  因為我
Is it too much of a problem to ask? 'Cause I'm...
-好吧  -我真的需要你幫忙
- Okay, okay. - I really need your help here.
好了
Okay.
有膿液
Oh, there's pus!
不是膿液
It's not pus.
是裝置釋放出的無機原生質
It's an inorganic plasmic discharge from the device,
-不是我身體分泌的  -好臭
- not from my body. - It smells!
是啊
Yeah, it does.
銅線  銅線  摸到了嗎
The copper wire. The copper wire, you got it?
-好  摸到了  -摸到了嗎
- Okay, I got it! I got it! - Okay, you got it?
拉出來時不要碰到槽壁
Now, don't let it touch the sides when you're coming out!
-我之前就是跟你強調這個  -抱歉
- That's what I was trying to tell you before. - I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
拉出來時  一定不要拉出...
Okay, now make sure that when you pull it out, you don't...
最末端的磁鐵
There's a magnet at the end of it!
就這個  你給拉出來了
That was it. You just pulled it out.
-天吶  -我沒想到...
- Oh, God! - Okay, I was not expecting...
-別放回去  -我怎么辦
- Don't put it back in! Don't put it back in! - Okay, what do I do?
怎么了
What's wrong?
沒事  我就是要心臟驟停了
Nothing, I'm just going into cardiac arrest
-因為你像撈魚一樣  -什么
- 'cause you yanked - What?
-把它揪出來了  -你不是說挺安全的嗎
- it out like a trout... - I though you said it was safe!
我們得快了  拿這個
We gotta hurry. Take this. Take this.
-迅速換好  -好
- You gotta switch it out really quick. - Okay. Okay.
-托尼  -什么
- Tony? - What?
-會沒事的  -是嗎
- It's going to be okay. - Is it?
不會有事的
It's gonna be okay.
-我會搞定的  -希望如此
- I'm gonna make this okay. - Let's hope.
把那個接到底盤上
Okay, you're gonna attach that to the base plate.
務必要
Make sure you...
很難嗎
Was that so hard?
挺好玩的吧
That was fun, right?
好了  給我吧
Here, I got it. I got it. Here.
好樣的
Nice.
-你沒事吧  -嗯  我很好  你沒事吧
- Are you okay? - Yeah, I feel great. You okay?
永遠永遠永遠
Don't ever, ever, ever,
別再要求我做這樣的事了
ever ask me to do anything like that ever again.
我只有你
I don't have anyone but you.
好了
Anyway...
-這個你要我怎么處理  -那個嗎
- What do you want me to do with this? - That?
毀掉
Destroy it.
焚毀
Incinerate it.
你不想留著嗎
You don't want to keep it?
派珀  人們說我有很多特點
Pepper, I've been called many things.
但不包括"懷舊"
"Nostalgic" is not one of them.
沒別的事了吧  斯塔克先生
Will that be all, Mr Stark?
沒事了  波茨小姐
That will be all, Miss Potts.
笨手笨腳  過來
Hey, Butterfingers, come here.
我桌上這堆東西怎么回事
What's all this stuff doing on top of my desk?
那是我的手機  那是我跟爸爸的合照
That's my phone, that's a picture of me and my dad.
那里  垃圾堆里
Right there. In the garbage. All that stuff.
空中戰斗的未來  是有人還是無人
The future of air combat. Is it manned or unmanned?
以我的經驗
I'll tell you, in my experience,
無人機永遠
no unmanned aerial vehicle
比不過飛行員的直覺
will ever trump a pilot's instinct,
見解
his insight,
以及看透表象
that ability to look into a situation beyond the obvious
確定結果的判斷力
and discern its outcome, or a pilot's judgement.
中校  何不讓飛行員擺脫飛機
Colonel? Why not a pilot without the plane?
看看是誰從天而降  托尼·斯塔克先生
Look who fell out of the sky. Mr Tony Stark.
-你好  先生  -說到有人無人[是不是男人]
- Hello, sir. - Speaking of manned or unmanned,
你們一定要問他
you gotta get him to tell you
有年春假猜錯答案的那次
about the time he guessed wrong at spring break.
記住  春假  1987年
Just remember that, spring break, 1987.
-跟你一起醒來的那位美麗女士  -別鬧
- That lovely lady you woke up with. - Don't do that!
-他叫什么來著  -別鬧
- What was his name? - Don't do that.
-埃文嗎  -別鬧
- Was it Ivan? - Don't do that.
他們會信的  別鬧
They'll believe it. Don't do that.
-好吧  -別鬧
- Okay. - Don't do that.
-認識你們很高興  -讓我們聊會兒
- Pleasure meeting you. - Give us a couple minutes, you guys.
-我很意外  -為什么
- I'm surprised. - Why?
我沒想到這么快就能見到你起來走動
I swear, I didn't expect to see you walking around so soon.
我可不止是走動
I'm doing a little better than walking.
-真的  -嗯
- Really? - Yeah.
羅德  我在研究個大項目
Rhodey, I'm working on something big.
我是來找你的  我希望你也參與進來
I came to talk to you. I want you to be a part of it.
你要讓這里
You're about to make
很多人開心起來了
a whole lot of people around here real happy,
因為之前記者招待會上的那個表演
'cause that little stunt at the press conference,
太逗了
that was a doozy.
這不是給軍隊的  我不...這不一樣
This is not for the military. I'm not... It's different.
怎么  你成人道主義者了
What? You're a humanitarian now or something?
-我需要你聽我說  -不
- I need you to listen to me. - No.
你需要時間把思緒理清楚
What you need is time to get your mind right.
-我說真的  -好吧
- I'm serious. - Okay.
很高興見到你  托尼
It's nice seeing you, Tony.
謝謝
Thanks.
賈維斯  你在嗎
Jarvis, you up?
為您  先生  永遠都在
For you, sir, always.
我想建立新項目文檔  標注為馬克2號
I'd like to open a new project file, index as Mark II.
要將文件存儲到斯塔克工業中央數據庫中嗎
Shall I store this on the Stark lndustries Central Database?
其實  我不知道現在能信任誰
Actually, I don't know who to trust right now.
直到我另說
Till further notice,
先把東西都存在我的私人服務器上吧
why don't we just keep everything on my private server?
在研究秘密項目嗎  先生
Working on a secret project, are we, sir?
我不希望這玩意落入壞人之手
I don't want this winding up in the wrong hands.
或許在我手里  它能做好事
Maybe in mine, it can actually do some good.
下一個  上去
Next. Up.
不是靴子  呆呆  這里  懂嗎
Not in the boot, Dummy. Right here. You got me?
別動  很好
Stay put. Nice.
你真沒用  往下到腳趾  我來吧
You're of no benefit at all. Move down to the toe. I got this.
好吧  對不起  我妨礙你了嗎
Okay, I'm sorry, am I in your way?
上去
Up.
算了  別動
Screw it. Don't even move.
你真是個悲劇
You are a tragedy.
好了  我們好好做吧
Okay, let's do this right.
開始量步  半米  正中央
Start mark, half a metre, and back and centre.
呆呆  精神點  準備滅火
Dummy, look alive. You're on standby for fire safety.
你  開拍
You, roll it.
好  啟動手動控制
Okay. Activate hand controls.
慢慢開始
We're gonna start off nice and easy.
看看10%的推進能量能否實現上升
We're gonna see if 10% thrust capacity achieves lift.
三
And three,
二
two,
一
one.
上2  好  定位
Up two. All right, set that.
我一直在摁鈴  沒聽到對講機響嗎
I've been buzzing you. Did you hear the intercom?
嗯  都...什么
Yeah, everything's... What?
-奧巴代亞在樓上  -好啊
- Obadiah's upstairs. - Great!
-要我怎么跟他說  -好  我就上去
- What would you like me to tell him? - Great. I'll be right up.
好
Okay.
你不是說你不做武器了嗎
I thought you said you were done making weapons.
是的
It is.
這是飛行穩定器  完全無害
This is a flight stabiliser. It's completely harmless.
這我沒料到
I didn't expect that.
怎么樣
How'd it go?
那么不順利啊
It went that bad, huh?
就因為我從紐約帶了披薩回來
Just because I brought pizza back from New York
不代表就不順利
doesn't mean it went bad.
當然了  天吶
Sure doesn't. Oh, boy.
如果你去了還能順利點
It would have gone better if you were there.
你叫我低調的  所以我照做了
You told me to lay low. That's what I've been doing.
我低調  你處理好...
I lay low, and you take care of all...
拜托  那是指在公眾  媒體面前
Hey, come on. In public. The press.
這可是董事會會議
This was a board of directors meeting.
是董事會會議嗎
This was a board of directors meeting?
董事會稱你患了創傷后應激癥
The board is claiming you have post traumatic stress.
他們提交了禁止令
They're filing an injunction.
-什么  -他們要阻攔你
- A what? - They want to lock you out.
怎么  因為股票跌了40點嗎
Why, 'cause the stocks dipped 40 points?
我們早知道會這樣
We knew that was gonna happen.
-是56.5  -這無所謂
- Fifty-six and a half. - It doesn't matter.
我們擁有公司的控股權
We own the controlling interest in the company.
托尼  董事會也有權利
Tony, the board has rights, too.
他們稱  你和你的新方向
They're making the case that you and your new direction
-對公司不是最有利的  -我這是負責任
- isn't in the company's best interest. - I'm being responsible!
這是我和公司的新方向
That's a new direction for me, for the company.
我要代表公司
I mean, me on the company's behalf
負起責任
being responsible for the way that...
這真好
This is great.
-得了  托尼  -我去工作室
- Oh, come on. Tony. Tony. - I'll be in the shop.
托尼  聽我說
Tony. Listen.
我在努力挽回局面
I'm trying to turn this thing around,
但你得給我點東西
but you gotta give me something.
拿給他們看的東西
Something to pitch them.
讓工程師分析下那個
Let me have the engineers analyse that.
畫出參數圖紙
You know, draw up some specs.
-不行  絕對不行  -讓我有根骨頭丟給
- No. No, absolutely not. - It'll give me a bone to throw the boys
-這個留在我身上  -紐約的人
- This one stays with me. - in New York!
就是這樣  奧比  別想了
That's it, Obie. Forget it.
好  那這個留在我這兒
All right, well, this stays with me, then.
來吧  你可以拿走一塊
Go on, here, you can have a piece.
-拿兩個吧  -謝謝
- Take two. - Thank you.
我可以下去看看你在做什么嗎
You mind if I come down there and see what you're doing?
晚安  奧比
Good night, Obie.
第11天  第37次測試  配置2.0
Day 11 , test 37, configuration 2.0.
因為沒有更好的選擇
For lack of a better option,
仍由呆呆負責滅火  你再敢噴我
Dummy is still on fire safety. If you douse me again,
而且是我沒著火時  我就把你捐給城市學院
and I'm not on fire, I'm donating you to a city college.
慢慢來
All right, nice and easy.
真的  就從1%推進能量開始
Seriously, just gonna start off with 1% thrust capacity.
三  二  一
And three, two, one.
好的
Okay.
別拿那玩意時刻指著我
Please don't follow me around with it, either,
讓我覺得我隨時會自燃
'cause I feel like I'm gonna catch on fire spontaneously.
退后點  如果真出事了再沖上來
Just stand down! If something happens, then come in.
再來  能量加到2.5%
And again, let's bring it up to 2.5.
三  二  一
Three, two, one.
好吧  我不想到這里來
Okay, this is where I don't want to be!
別燒車
Not the car, not the car!
桌子
Table!
還算可以  沒事的
Could be worse! Could be worse! We're fine!
好
Okay.
不
No!
好啊  我能飛了
Yeah, I can fly.
-賈維斯  在嗎  -隨時候命  先生
- Jarvis, are you there? - At your service, sir.
-啟動前置顯示  -已啟動
- Engage Heads Up Display. - Check.
從本地界面輸入偏好
Import all preferences from home interface.
好的  先生
Will do, sir.
好  怎么樣
All right, what do you say?
我已經上傳好了  先生
I have indeed been uploaded, sir.
我們已經上線  準備好了
We're online and ready.
可以開始虛擬行走嗎
Can we start the virtual walk-around?
正在輸入偏好  校準虛擬環境
Importing preferences and calibrating virtual environment.
檢查控制表面
Do a check on control surfaces.
如您所愿
As you wish.
測試完成  準備關機  開始診斷
Test complete. Preparing to power down and begin diagnostics.
嗯  這樣吧  檢查天氣和航空管制
Yeah. Tell you what. Do a weather and ATC check.
并監聽地面控制
Start listening in on ground control.
先生  真正飛行之前
Sir, there are still terabytes
還需要進行兆兆字節的計算
of calculations needed before an actual flight is...
賈維斯  有時候要先跑才能走
Jarvis! Sometimes you got to run before you can walk.
準備好了嗎  三  二  一
Ready? In three, two, one.
操作流暢
Handles like a dream.
好了  看看這玩意的本事如何
All right, let's see what this thing can do.
SR-71偵察機的記錄是多少
What's SR-71's record?
固定翼飛行的飛行高度記錄為8.5萬英尺
The altitude record for fixed wing flight is 85,000 feet, sir.
記錄就是用來打破的  來啊
Records are made to be broken! Come on!
先生  出現了可能致命的結冰
Sir, there is a potentially fatal buildup of ice occurring.
繼續走
Come on!
再高點
Higher!
我們結冰了  賈維斯  展開襟翼
We iced up, Jarvis! Deploy flaps!
賈維斯
Jarvis!
拜托  我們得除冰
Come on, we got to break the ice!
關閉動力
Kill power.
派珀送
托尼·斯塔克有心的證明
記錄  主傳感器在4萬英尺以上變得遲緩
Notes. Main transducer feels sluggish at plus 40 altitude.
殼體增壓是個問題
Hull pressurisation is problematic.
我認為結冰可能是影響因素
I'm thinking icing is the probable factor.
觀察敏銳  先生
A very astute observation, sir.
或許  如果您打算造訪其他星球
Perhaps, if you intend to visit other planets,
我們應該改進排氣系統
we should improve the exo systems.
與思科連接  重新配置外殼金屬
Connect to the Cisco. Have it reconfigure the shell metals.
使用六翼天使戰術衛星的金鈦合金
Use the gold titanium alloy from the seraphim tactical satellite.
這樣應該能保證外殼不受損
That should ensure a fuselage integrity
而不影響動力-重量比
while maintaining power-to-weight ratio.
-知道了嗎  -是
- Got it? - Yes.
我要按提議方案進行渲染嗎
Shall I render using proposed specifications?
好好發揮吧
Thrill me.
今晚迪士尼音樂廳的
Tonight's red-hot red carpet is right here
紅毯異常火熱
at the Disney Concert Hall,
托尼·斯塔克第三屆年度
where Tony Stark's third annual
消防員家屬基金會慈善晚會在此舉辦
benefit for the Firefighter's Family Fund
洛杉磯上流社會蜂擁而至
has become the place to be for L.A.'s high society.
賈維斯  我們收到邀請了嗎
Jarvis, we get an invite for that?
我沒有邀請的記錄  先生
I have no record of an invitation, sir.
自從那場怪異
...hasn't been seen in public
且極具爭議的記者招待會后就未曾公開露面
since his bizarre and highly controversial press conference.
有些人稱他患有創傷后應激癥
Some claim he's suffering from post traumatic stress
已經臥床數周  不管真相如何
and has been bedridden for weeks. Whatever the case may be,
沒有人指望他今晚出現
no one expects an appearance from him tonight.
渲染已完成
The render is complete.
有點招搖了吧
A little ostentatious, don't you think?
我怎么想的  您一般都很低調的
What was I thinking? You're usually so discreet.
這樣吧  加上點火紅色
Tell you what. Throw a little hot-rod red in there.
嗯  這樣就低調了
Yes, that should help you keep a low profile.
渲染完成
The render is complete.
我喜歡  制造上色吧
Hey, I like it. Fabricate it. Paint it.
開始自動組裝
Commencing automated assembly.
估計完成時間  五小時
Estimated completion time is five hours.
別等我了  親愛的
Don't wait up for me, honey.
武器制造
Weapons manufacturing
只是斯塔克工業的一小部分
is only one small part of what Stark Industries is all about,
我們與火災救援群體的合作
and our partnership with the fire and rescue community...
-托尼  記得我嗎  -完全不
- Hey, Tony, remember me? - Sure don't.
氣色真不錯  海夫
You look great, Hef.
這一季我們會表現出色的
We're going to have a great quarter.
這世界是怎么了
What's the world coming to
來自己的派對都沒有請柬
when a guy's got to crash his own party?
看看你
Look at you.
真是意外
Hey, what a surprise.
里面見
I'll see you inside.
聽著  悠著點
Listen, take it slow, all right?
我覺得我已經安撫好董事會了
I think I got the board right where we want them.
好嘞  我就是憋壞了  就玩一會兒
You got it. Just cabin fever. I'll just be a minute.
給我杯威士忌  我餓死了
Give me a Scotch. I'm starving.
斯塔克先生
Mr Stark?
-怎么  -科爾森特工
- Yeah? - Agent Coulson.
是啊  你是那個...
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. The guy from the...
國土戰略防御
Strategic Homeland Intervention,
攻擊與后勤保障局
Enforcement and Logistics Division.
天吶  你們需要新名字了
God, you need a new name for that.
是啊  我常聽人這么說
Yeah, I hear that a lot.
聽著  我知道您現在一定很不容易
Listen, I know this must be a trying time for you,
但我們需要了解情況
but we need to debrief you.
還有很多問題未得到解答
There's still a lot of unanswered questions,
這種事情  時間有時很重要
and time can be a factor with these things.
我們約個時間吧
Let's just put something on the books.
24日晚7點在斯塔克工業見如何
How about the 24th at 7:00 p.m. at Stark Industries?
這樣吧  說定了  你說得很對
Tell you what. You got it. You're absolutely right.
我去找我助理  定個日子
Well, I'm going to go to my assistant, and we'll make a date.
你太美了  我都沒認出你來
You look fantastic! I didn't recognise you.
-你怎么來了  -回避政府特工
- What are you doing here? - Just avoiding government agents.
-你一個人來的嗎  -嗯  裙子哪來的
- Are you by yourself? - Yes. Where'd you get that dress?
-是生日禮物  -太棒了
- Oh, it was a birthday present. - That's great.
-你送的  -我的品位真棒
- From you, actually. - Well, I got great taste.
是啊
Yes.
-想跳舞嗎  -不
- You want to dance? - Oh, no.
-來嘛  -謝謝了  不
- All right, come on. - Thank you. No.
我讓你不舒服了嗎
Am I making you uncomfortable?
沒有
No. No.
我總忘記擦除臭劑
I always forget to wear deodorant
還當著我所有同事的面穿一件露背裙子
and dance with my boss in front of everyone that I work with
跟我的老板跳舞
in a dress with no back.
-你很美  也很香  -天吶
- You look great and you smell great. - Oh, God.
但如果能讓你舒服點  我可以解雇你
But I could fire you if that would take the edge off.
我覺得沒了我你恐怕都不會系鞋帶了
I actually don't think that you could tie your shoes without me.
-我能撐一周  -是嗎
- I'd make it a week. - Really?
-絕對的  -你的社保號碼是多少
- Sure. - What's your Social Security number?
-五  -五
- Five. - Five?
-好吧  -嗯
- Right. - Right.
-你漏了幾位數字  -另外八個嗎
- You're missing just a couple of digits there. - The other eight?
另外八個有你嘛
So I got you for the other eight.
-出去透口氣吧  -嗯  我需要透口氣
- How about a little air? - Yes, I need some air.
-那感覺太怪了  -完全沒關系
- That was totally weird. - Totally harmless.
才不是沒關系
It was totally not harmless, by the way.
我們跳了支舞
We're dancing.
-都沒人看  -我的所有同事
- No one's even watching. - Everybody who I work with...
不是的  知道為什么嗎
No, you know why?
我覺得你不夠客觀
I think you lost objectivity.
我覺得他們就是...人而已
I think they just... People...
我們就是跳了個舞
We just danced.
不  不只是跳舞
No, it was not just a dance.
你不懂  因為你是你
You don't understand because you're you.
所有人都清楚你是什么樣的人
And everybody knows exactly who you are
你怎么對待女人什么的
and how you are with girls and all of that,
這沒什么關系
which is completely fine.
但我  你是我的老板
But, you know, then me, you're my boss,
我跟你跳舞
and I'm dancing with you.
-我覺得沒人會那么想的  -這讓我顯得
- I don't think it was taken that way. - Because it makes me look like
好像在
the one who's trying to...
-我覺得你想多了  -我們又來到這里
- I just think you're overstating it. - You know, and we're here,
我還穿著這件荒唐的
and then I'm wearing this ridiculous
裙子  我們還那樣跳舞
dress, and then we were dancing like that and...
-我想喝杯酒  謝謝  -好嘞
- I would like a drink, please. - Got it, okay.
-伏特加馬丁尼  謝謝  -好
- I would like a vodka martini, please. - Okay.
不加水  要很多橄欖
Very dry with olives, a lot of olives.
至少三顆
Like, at least three olives.
兩杯伏特加馬丁尼
Two vodka martinis,
不加水  多加橄欖  趕快
extra dry, extra olives, extra fast.
其中一杯加橄欖汁
Make one of them dirty, will you?
托尼·斯塔克
Tony Stark.
居然在這里見到了你
Fancy seeing you here.
-卡莉  -克莉絲汀
- Carrie. - Christine.
沒錯
That's right.
你今晚居然敢來
You have a lot of nerve showing up here tonight.
你至少能給個反應嗎
Can I at least get a reaction from you?
慌張  我認為我的反應是慌張
Panic. I would say panic is my reaction.
我是指你公司與最近
'Cause I was referring to your company's
一宗慘案的關系
involvement in this latest atrocity.
是啊  他們向我發了邀請
Yeah. They just put my name on the invitation.
我不知道能說什么
I don't know what to tell you.
我真的差點相信了
I actually almost bought it, hook, line and sinker.
我出門了幾個月  沒聽說嗎
I was out of town for a couple months, in case you didn't hear.
這就是你所謂的負責任嗎
Is this what you call accountability?
這里叫科米拉  聽說過嗎
It's a town called Gulmira. Heard of it?
斯塔克工業
-這是什么時候拍的  -昨天
- When were these taken? - Yesterday.
-我沒有準許運輸  -你的公司準許了
- I didn't approve any shipment. - Well, your company did.
我不是我的公司
Well, I'm not my company.
-請回避一下  -你見過這些照片嗎
- Please, do you mind? - Have you seen these pictures?
-科米拉發生了什么  -托尼
- What's going on in Gulmira? - Tony, Tony.
你不能這么天真
You can't afford to be this naive.
我曾經很天真
You know what? I was naive before,
他們說  "這條線  我們不要越過
when they said, "Here's the line. We don't cross it.
我們就這么做生意"
This is how we do business."
如果我們暗地里做了兩面派  我們有嗎
If we're double-dealing under the table... Are we?
托尼  拍張照吧
Tony, your picture, please!
我們拍張照吧  來吧
Let's take a picture. Come on.
拍照片了
Picture time!
托尼  你以為是誰排擠了你
Tony. Who do you think locked you out?
是我提出了針對你的禁止令
I was the one who filed the injunction against you.
只有這樣我才能保護你
It was the only way I could protect you.
不
No. No.
到達科米拉外圍的15英里路程
The 15-mile hike to the outskirts of Gulmira
只能被形容為墮入地獄之路
can only be described as a descent into hell,
進入當代的黑暗之心
into a modern day Heart of Darkness.
來自和平村莊的普通的農民和牧民
Simple farmers and herders from peaceful villages
被迫離開家園
have been driven from their homes,
被軍閥趕出了他們的土地
displaced from their lands by warlords
新得的力量為這些人壯了膽
emboldened by a new-found power.
村民們被迫居住在
Villagers have been forced to take shelter
其他村莊的廢墟中
in whatever crude dwellings they can find
簡陋的遮蔽處里
in the ruins of other villages,
或是躲在這棟舊蘇聯冶煉廠遺址里
or here in the remnants of an old Soviet smelting plant.
最近的暴力事件
Recent violence has been
被歸咎于一群外國士兵
attributed to a group of foreign fighters
他們被當地人稱為十戒組織
referred to by locals as the Ten Rings.
可以看到  他們軍備齊全  而且目的明確
As you can see, these men are heavily armed and on a mission.
任何妨礙了他們的人
A mission that could prove fatal
都可能因此喪命
to anyone who stands in their way.
因為沒有政治干預或國際壓力
With no political will or international pressure,
這些難民希望渺茫
there's very little hope for these refugees.
我身邊的一個女人  在焦急等待丈夫的消息
Around me, a woman begging for news on her husband,
他被叛亂分子綁架了
who was kidnapped by insurgents,
不知是被強迫加入他們的軍隊...
either forced to join their militia...
焦急的難民抓著泛黃的照片
Desperate refugees clutch yellowed photographs,
給任何愿意駐足的人看
holding them up to anyone who will stop.
孩子簡單的問題  "我的媽媽爸爸在哪"
A child's simple question, "Where are my mother and father?"
難民們希望渺茫
There's very little hope for these refugees,
難民們只能想著  是否會有人來幫忙
refugees who can only wonder who, if anyone, will help.
快點
Hurry it up.
把女人趕上車
Put the women in the trucks.
把武器存放在這里
Stack the weapons here.
把房子清空
Clear all the houses.
那個  快點
That one there. Faster. Faster.
抓住那家伙
Grab that dog.
把他跟其他人放在一起
Put him with the others.
這怎么回事
What the hell is this?
打死這家伙
Shoot this dog.
你們這群沒用的東西
You're all incompetent.
腦袋轉過去
Turn your head.
他交給你們了
He's all yours.
那是什么玩意  我們準許去那里了嗎
What the hell was that? Were we cleared to go in there?
加州  愛德華茲空軍基地
那是什么玩意  我們準許去那里了嗎
What the hell was that? Were we cleared to go in there?
沒有  長官  他們用了人肉盾
No, sir, they were using human shields.
加州  愛德華茲空軍基地
我們沒獲得批準
We never got the green light.
加州  愛德華茲空軍基地
給我接國務院  肯定是他們搞的
Put me through to State. They're going to be all over this.
加州  愛德華茲空軍基地
給我接國務院  肯定是他們搞的
Put me through to State. They're going to be all over this.
調出顯示
Get those monitors up!
發現不明物體
We got a bogey!
-不是空軍  -接通中情局了嗎
- Wasn't Air Force! - We got the CIA on the line?
我接通了蘭利  他們還問是不是我們
I've got Langley on the line. They want to know if it's us.
絕對不是我們  長官
No, it definitely is not us, sir!
-不是海軍  -不是陸戰隊
- It wasn't Navy. - Wasn't Marines.
我需要答案  能拿到目標圖像嗎
I need answers! Can I please get eyes on target?
-不能  -無法識別
- Negative, negative. - Cannot identify.
馬上把武器研發的羅德中校叫來
Get me Colonel Rhodes from Weapons Development down here now!
我們查了身份
We ran an ID check
并交叉對比了所有已知數據庫
and cross-referenced with all known databases.
毫無發現
We have nothing.
當地有高空監控嗎
Any high altitude surveillance in the region?
當地有空中早期預警和全球鷹
We got an AWAC and a Global Hawk in the area.
這玩意是突然冒出來的嗎
So this thing just appeared out of nowhere?
怎么會沒在雷達上發現
How come it didn't show up on the radar?
只有很小的雷達截面  長官
Got a minimal radar cross-section, sir.
-隱形的嗎  -不是  長官  它很小
- Is it stealth? - No, sir, it's tiny.
應該是無人機
We think it's an unmanned aerial vehicle.
中校  這是什么情況
Colonel, what are we dealing with here?
-我去打個電話  -中士  清條線路
- Let me make a call. - Sergeant, clear a hole.
-喂  -托尼
- Hello? - Tony?
-誰啊  -羅德
- Who's this? - It's Rhodes.
-抱歉  誰  -我說是羅德
- Sorry, hello? - I said it's Rhodes.
-請大點聲  -那是什么噪音
- Speak up, please. - What in the hell is that noise?
嗯  我敞篷開車呢
Oh, yeah, I'm driving with the top down.
我現在需要你幫忙
Yeah, well, I need your help right now.
天道好輪回啊
It's funny how that works, huh?
是啊  是這樣
Yeah. Speaking of funny,
有個武器站剛被炸毀了
we've got a weapons depot that was just blown up
離你當初被囚的地方只有幾公里
a few clicks from where you were being held captive.
那里挺危險的
Well, that's a hot spot.
似乎是有人插手替你完成了工作  是吧
Sounds like someone stepped in and did your job for you, huh?
你為什么氣喘吁吁的  托尼
Why do you sound out of breath, Tony?
我沒有  我在峽谷里慢跑呢
I'm not, I was justjogging in the canyon.
-你不是在開車嗎  -是啊  我開車
- I thought you were driving. - Right, I was driving
到了峽谷  然后去慢跑
to the canyon, where I'm going to jog.
你在那一帶真沒有什么
You sure you don't have any tech
我應該知道的東西嗎
in that area I should know about?
-沒有  -發現不明物體了
- Nope! - Bogey spotted!
鞭子戰機  正在前往
Whiplash, come in hot.
很好  因為我眼前就有個東西
Okay, good, 'cause I'm staring at one right now,
馬上要被炸飛了
and it's about to be blown to kingdom come.
我該撤了
That's my exit.
戰情室  這里是鞭子一號
Ballroom, this is Whiplash One.
我看到不明物體了
I've got the bogey in my sights.
鞭子一號  那是什么玩意
Whiplash One, what is it?
我不知道
I've got no idea.
-能進行無線電聯絡嗎  -無反應  長官
- You have radio contact? - Non responsive, sir.
那你可以交火
Then you are clear to engage.
超音速飛行
啟動
Hit it.
超音速飛行
啟動
Hit it.
不明物體剛進入了超音速  我鎖定了
That bogey just went supersonic. I got a lock!
-導彈來襲  -照明彈
- lnbound missile. - Flares!
等等  不明物體調用了照明彈
Wait a second. Bogey deployed flares!
展開襟翼
Deploy flaps!
我去
Holy!
那玩意從雷達上消失了  長官
That thing just jumped off the radar, sir.
衛星盯丟了
The sat visual has been lost.
那絕不是無人機
No way that's a UAV.
是什么
What is it?
我什么都看不到
I can't see anything.
不管是什么  剛剛已經死了
Whatever it was, it just bought the farm.
不明物體應該已經被處理掉了  長官
I think bogey's been handled, sir.
-喂  -羅德  是我
- Hello? - Hi, Rhodey, it's me.
-誰  -抱歉  確實是我
- It's who? - I'm sorry, it is me.
你問了  你問的那個就是我
You asked. What you were asking about is me.
瞧  這不是游戲
No, see, this isn't a game.
你不能把平民裝備飛入我的活動戰區
You do not send civilian equipment into my active war zone.
-你懂不懂  -不是一件裝備
- You understand that? - This is not a piece of equipment.
我在里面呢  是件戰衣  那是我
I'm in it. It's a suit. It's me!
羅德  你查到什么了嗎
Rhodey, you got anything for me?
-標記位置  回基地  -收到  戰情室
- Mark your position and return to base. - Roger that, Ballroom.
在你底下
On your belly!
像是個人
lt looks like a man!
甩掉他  翻滾
Shake him off! Roll! Roll!
我被打中了
I'm hit! I'm hit!
確認  他被擊中了
It's confirmed. He has been hit.
跳傘
Punch out! Punch out!
鞭子一號墜機
Whiplash One down.
鞭子二號  看到降落傘了嗎
Whiplash Two, do you see a chute?
沒有  沒有降落傘
Negative! No chute, no chute!
我的降落傘卡住了
My chute's jammed!
長官  我看到不明物體了
Sir, I've got a visual on the bogey.
鞭子二號  再次出擊
Whiplash Two, reengage.
如果能擊落  就擊落
If you get a clear shot, you take it.
少校  我們都不知道那是什么
Major, we don't even know what we're shooting at.
讓猛禽回來
Call off the Raptors.
那玩意剛在合法禁飛區內
That thing just took out an F- 22
擊落了一架F22
inside a legal no fly zone!
鞭子二號  如果能擊落  就擊落
Whiplash Two, if you have a clear shot, take it!
你又被鎖定了  進行躲避操作
You've been reengaged. Execute evasive manoeuvre.
繼續飛
Keep going!
降落傘打開
Good chute! Good chute!
-托尼  你還在嗎  -謝謝了
- Tony, you still there? - Hey, thanks.
天吶  你個瘋子
Oh, my God, you crazy son of a bitch.
你欠我架飛機  你知道吧
You owe me a plane. You know that, right?
嚴格講  是他撞了我
Yeah, well, technically, he hit me.
你要過來看看我在做什么嗎
Now are you going to come by and see what I'm working on?
不要  我知道得越少越好
No, no, no, no, no, no, the less I know, the better.
我要怎么跟媒體講
Now, what am I supposed to tell the press?
演練  一般不都用這套屁話嗎
Training exercise. Isn't that the usual BS?
沒那么簡單
It's not that simple.
昨天一架猛禽F22
An unfortunate training exercise
在演練中不幸發生事故
involving an F-22 Raptor occurred yesterday.
慶幸的是  飛行員并未受傷
I am pleased to report that the pilot was not injured.
至于科米拉村莊意料之外的局勢反轉
As for the unexpected turn of events on the ground in Gulmira,
是誰或是什么進行了干預  我們尚不清楚
it is still unclear who or what intervened,
但我可以保證
but I can assure you that
此事與美國政府無關
the United States government was not involved.
的確很貼身  先生
It is a tight fit, sir.
先生  您越是扭動  就會越疼
Sir, the more you struggle, the more this is going to hurt.
溫柔點  這是我第一次
Be gentle. This is my first time.
我設計它能脫下來的  所以
I designed this to come off, so...
我真的應該能
I really should be able to...
請盡量不要動  先生
Please, try not to move, sir.
怎么回事啊
What's going on here?
承認吧
Let's face it.
這不是你撞見我做的最糟糕的事
This is not the worst thing you've caught me doing.
那是彈孔嗎
Are those bullet holes?
歡迎
Welcome.
托尼·斯塔克的贈禮
Compliments of Tony Stark.
如果你當初按計劃殺了他
If you'd killed him when you were supposed to,
也不會把臉燒掉了
you'd still have a face.
你給我們點小錢殺一位王子
You paid us trinkets to kill a prince.
帶我去看武器
Show me the weapon.
來吧  讓守衛留在外面
Come. Leave your guards outside.
他的逃脫帶來了意外的收獲
His escape bore unexpected fruit.
他就是這么做到的
So this is how he did it.
這只是首次的粗糙的嘗試
This is only a first, crude effort.
斯塔克已完善了他的設計
Stark has perfected his design.
他制作了一件死亡杰作
He has made a masterpiece of death.
有十幾件這種戰衣的人  能統治亞洲
A man with a dozen of these can rule all of Asia.
你夢想奪下斯塔克的王位
And you dream of Stark's throne.
我們有共同的敵人
We have a common enemy.
如果我們還在合作
If we are still in business,
我會把設計給你
I will give you these designs
當做禮物
as a gift.
作為交換
And in turn,
希望你能禮尚往來
I hope you'll repay me
給我鋼鐵戰士
with a gift of iron soldiers.
這是你唯一會得到的禮物
This is the only gift you shall receive.
科技
Technology.
在世界的這一帶一直是個致命弱點
It's always been your Achilles' heel in this part of the world.
別擔心  只會持續15分鐘
Don't worry. It'll only last for 1 5 minutes.
這是你最不需要擔心的事了
That's the least of your problems.
把裝甲和其余的裝箱帶走
Crate up the armour and the rest of it.
好  我們做個了結吧
All right, let's finish up here.
讓方舟反應堆下的16區做好準備
Set up Sector 16 underneath the arc reactor,
我需要遮蔽這些數據
and I'm going to want this data masked.
找來我們最好的工程師
Recruit our top engineers.
馬上給我造個原型機
I want a prototype right away.
你忙嗎  可以替我去辦件事嗎
You busy? You mind if I send you on an errand?
我需要你去我辦公室
I need you to go to my office.
黑入主機
You're going to hack into the mainframe
拿到所有最近的運輸清單
and you're going to retrieve all the recent shipping manifests.
這是鎖定芯片
This is a lock chip.
能讓你黑進去
This'll get you in.
大概是在執行文檔里
It's probably under Executive Files.
要不  就是在幽靈驅動上
If not, they put it on a ghost drive,
那樣的話  你就得查找標題數碼最小的
in which case you need to look for the lowest numeric heading.
如果我拿回了信息
And what do you plan to do with this information
你打算怎么做呢
if I bring it back here?
還是那套
Same drill.
他們在暗箱操作  我要阻止他們
They've been dealing under the table, and I'm going to stop them.
我要找到我的武器  摧毀它們
I'm going to find my weapons and destroy them.
托尼
Tony,
你知道我愿幫你做任何事
you know that I would help you with anything,
但如果你又要這么胡來  我就不能幫你
but I cannot help you if you're going to start all of this again.
除了這個  別無其他  沒有藝術館開幕
There is nothing except this. There's no art opening.
或是慈善晚會  或是簽什么字
There is no benefit. There is nothing to sign.
只有下一項任務  沒有別的
There is the next mission and nothing else.
是嗎
Is that so?
那我辭職
Well, then, I quit.
這么多年來  你一直在我身邊
You stood by my side all these years
看著我收獲毀滅的利益
while I reaped the benefits of destruction.
現在我想保護那些
And now that I'm trying to protect the people
因我而身陷危險的人  你卻要走人嗎
that I put in harm's way, you're going to walk out?
你會害死自己的  托尼
You're going to kill yourself, Tony.
我不要助你一臂之力
I'm not going to be a part of it.
我本不該活下來的
I shouldn't be alive,
除非這有什么意義
unless it was for a reason.
我沒瘋  派珀
I'm not crazy, Pepper.
我就是終于知道  我該做什么了
I just finally know what I have to do.
我心里知道  這是對的
And I know in my heart that it's right.
你也是我的一切了
You're all I have, too, you know.
警告  安全漏洞
準許訪問
找到幽靈驅動
16區  讀取文檔
16區
Sector 16?
16區  讀取文檔
你在干什么  奧巴代亞
What are you up to, Obadiah?
翻譯
你可沒說你付錢叫我們殺的目標
You did not tell us that the target you paid us to kill
是了不起的托尼·斯塔克
was the great Tony Stark.
-你可以看到  -天吶
- As you can see, - Oh, my God.
奧巴代亞·斯坦尼
Obadiah Stane...
你的欺騙和謊言會讓你付出高額代價
...your deception and lies will cost you dearly.
殺托尼·斯塔克的價錢剛剛漲了
The price to kill Tony Stark has just gone up.
開始復制
殺托尼·斯塔克的價錢剛剛漲了
The price to kill Tony Stark has just gone up.
開始復制
那么  我們要怎么辦
So, what are we going to do about this?
我理解你現在的處境  派珀
I know what you're going through, Pepper.
托尼  他的東西總是好的  是吧
Tony. He always gets the good stuff, doesn't he?
他回家時我好開心
I was so happy when he came home.
就好像他死而復生了
It was like we got him back from the dead.
現在我意識到
Now I realise,
托尼其實根本沒有回家來  是吧
well, Tony never really did come home, did he?
他把自己的一部分留在了那個洞里
He left a part of himself in that cave.
傷透了我的心
Breaks my heart.
他是個復雜的人
Well, he's a complicated person.
他經受了很多事  我覺得他會沒事的
He's been through a lot. I think he'll be all right.
你真是個少見的女人
You are a very rare woman.
托尼不知道自己多么幸運
Tony doesn't know how lucky he is.
謝謝你  謝謝
Thank you. Thanks.
我得回去了
I'd better get back there.
那是今天的報紙嗎
Is that today's paper?
是啊
Yes.
能給我看看嗎
Do you mind?
-沒問題  -填字謎
- Not at all. - Puzzle.
當然
Of course.
保重
Take care.
下載完成
波茨小姐  我們預約好的
Ms Potts? We had an appointment.
你忘記了我們的約會嗎
Did you forget about our appointment?
沒有  就現在  跟我來
Nope, right now. Come with me.
-現在  -我們現在就談
- Right now? - We're going to have it right now.
-對  跟我走  -好
- Yeah, walk with me. - Okay.
我要跟你好好談談  包你一輩子不忘
I'm going to give you the meeting of your life.
去你辦公室
Your office.
我們一直在盡力而為
Yeah, we've been working our best to do it.
當然  我們...我回頭打給你
Absolutely, we're... I'm going to have to call you back.
斯坦尼先生
Mr Stane?
先生  我們嘗試了您的要求
Sir, we've explored what you've asked us,
但似乎遇到了點小小障礙
and it seems as though there's a little hiccup.
-其實  -障礙
- Actually... - A hiccup?
是的  為給戰衣供能
Yes, to power the suit,
先生  那種科技尚不存在
sir, the technology actually doesn't exist.
-所以  -等等  科技
- So it's... - Wait, wait, wait. The technology?
威廉  這就是那個科技
William, here is the technology.
我只是叫你把它造小點
I've asked you to simply make it smaller.
好  先生  我們也在努力嘗試
Okay, sir, and that's what we're trying to do,
但老實說  這不可能
but honestly, it's impossible.
托尼·斯塔克在一個山洞里就造成了
Tony Stark was able to build this in a cave!
用的是一堆破爛
With a box of scraps!
對不起  我不是托尼·斯塔克
Well, I'm sorry. I'm not Tony Stark.
派珀·波茨來電
托尼
Tony?
托尼  你在嗎  喂
Tony, are you there? Hello?
呼吸
Breathe.
放松
Easy, easy.
你記得這個吧
You remember this one, right?
真可惜政府沒批準
It's a shame the government didn't approve it.
誘發短暫麻痹用途多廣泛啊
There's so many applications for causing short-term paralysis.
托尼
Tony.
我找人殺你時
When I ordered the hit on you,
我還擔心
I worried that I was
我是殺了金鵝
killing the golden goose.
但是
But, you see,
那真是
it was just
命運  你偏偏活了下來
fate that you survived that.
你還要給出最后一枚金蛋
You had one last golden egg to give.
你真以為
Do you really think
你想了個點子  它就是你的了嗎
that just because you have an idea, it belongs to you?
你父親
Your father,
他幫忙造了原子彈
he helped give us the atomic bomb.
如果他像你這么自私
Now, what kind of world would it be today
現在的世界會是什么樣啊
if he was as selfish as you?
真是美麗
Oh, it's beautiful.
托尼  這是你的第九交響樂
Tony, this is your Ninth Symphony.
西方迷信
貝多芬創作完成第九交響樂后不久便離世
他之后的很多作曲家也都是如此
真是杰作  看啊
What a masterpiece. Look at that.
這是你的遺產
This is your legacy.
新一代的武器
A new generation of weapons
將有它作為心臟
with this at its heart.
這些武器會把世界拉回正軌
Weapons that will help steer the world back on course,
讓權力落在我們手中
put the balance of power in our hands.
合適的手中
The right hands.
真希望你能看到我的原型機
I wish you could see my prototype.
雖然不像
It's not as...
不像你的那個那么保守
Well, not as conservative as yours.
可惜你還把派珀卷了進來
Too bad you had to involve Pepper in this.
我本來更想留她一命的
I would have preferred that she lived.
什么意思  他花錢雇人去殺托尼
What do you mean, he paid to have Tony killed?
派珀  慢點說  奧巴代亞為什么要
Pepper, slow down. Why would Obadiah...
好吧  托尼現在在哪
Okay, where's Tony now?
我不知道  他不接電話
I don't know. He's not answering his phone.
請你過去一趟  確保他沒事
Please go over there and make sure everything's okay.
謝謝  羅德  我知道條近路
Thank you, Rhodey. I know a shortcut.
乖
Good boy.
托尼
Tony?
Tony!
托尼
托尼  你沒事吧
Tony! You okay?
派珀呢
Where's Pepper?
她沒事  她身邊有五個特工呢
She's fine. She's with five agents.
他們要去逮捕奧巴代亞了
They're about to arrest Obadiah.
那不夠
That's not going to be enough.
16區
Section 16.
在那兒呢
There it is.
我的鑰匙沒用  打不開門
My key's not working. It's not opening the door.
那是什么  小裝置嗎
What's that? It's, like, a little device?
能開鎖嗎
It's, like, a thing that's going to pick the lock?
你最好退后幾步
You might want to take a few steps back.
那真是我見過的最酷的東西
That's the coolest thing I've ever seen.
不賴吧
Not bad, huh?
我們來吧
Let's do it.
還需要我做什么嗎
You need me to do anything else?
別讓人上天攪局
Keep the skies clear.
我去
Damn!
下次吧  寶貝
Next time, baby.
看來你是對的  他是在造戰衣
Looks like you were right. He was building a suit.
我以為會更大些呢
I thought it'd be bigger.
干掉他
Take him out!
你覺得馬克1號的胸膛電源能不能撐得住
How do you think the Mark I chest piece is going to hold up?
戰衣電力為48%  還在減少  先生
The suit's at 48% power and falling, sir.
這塊胸膛電源不是設計用來飛行的
That chest piece was never designed for sustained flight.
隨時通知我情況
Keep me posted.
派珀
Pepper!
托尼  你沒事吧
Tony! Tony, are you okay?
我沒事  你怎么...
I'm fine. How are...
-奧巴代亞  他瘋了  -我知道
- Obadiah, he's gone insane! - I know.
-你最好趕緊走  -他建了套戰衣
- Listen, you'd better get out of there. - He built a suit.
快點  馬上走
Get out of there right now!
你想去哪
Where do you think you're going?
我不再需要你的服務了
Your services are no longer required.
斯坦尼
Stane!
我愛這套戰衣
I love this suit!
-把他們放下  -附帶傷害  托尼
- Put them down! - Collateral damage, Tony.
向胸膛轉移能量
Divert power to chest RT.
能量僅剩19%
Power reduced to 19%.
女士
Lady!
不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no!
30年了  我一直捧著你
For 30 years, I've been holding you up!
我從零建立起了這家公司
I built this company from nothing!
什么都別想妨礙我
Nothing is going to stand in my way.
你更別想
Least of all you!
厲害  你升級了你的盔甲
Impressive! You've upgraded your armour!
我自己也有升級
I've made some upgrades of my own!
先生  他的戰衣似乎能飛
Sir, it appears that his suit can fly.
發現了  帶我飛到最高高度
Duly noted. Take me to maximum altitude.
現在只有15%的電力
With only 15% power,
達到這高度的可能性
the odds of reaching that...
我會算算數  照做
I know the math! Do it!
長官  你不會相信的  那玩意回來了
Sir, you're not going to believe this. That thing is back.
接艾倫少校  集結飛機
Get me Major Allen. Scramble the jets!
不必了  各位  只是演練
Not necessary, people. Just a training exercise.
是  長官
Yes, sir.
只剩13%的電力了  先生
Thirteen percent power, sir.
繼續爬升
Climb!
-11%  -繼續飛
- Eleven percent. - Keep going!
-電力為7%  -在屏幕上顯示就行
- Seven percent power. - Just leave it on the screen!
別說了
Stop telling me!
你的點子很棒  托尼
You had a great idea, Tony,
但我的戰衣在各方面都更先進
but my suit is more advanced in every way!
你怎么解決結冰問題的
How'd you solve the icing problem?
什么結冰問題
Icing problem?
最好查看一下
Might want to look into it.
2%
Two percent.
現在在使用緊急備用電力
We are now running on emergency backup power.
-波茨  -托尼  天吶  你沒事吧
- Potts! - Tony! Oh, my God, are you okay?
我快沒電了
I'm almost out of power.
我得脫掉戰衣  我就過去
I've got to get out of this thing. I'll be right there.
想得美
Nice try!
武器狀態
Weapons status?
沖擊系統下線  導彈下線
Repulsors offline. Missiles offline.
燃燒彈
Flares!
真聰明  托尼
Very clever, Tony.
-波茨  -托尼
- Potts? - Tony!
這樣不行
This isn't working.
我們得過載反應堆  炸碎屋頂
We're going to have to overload the reactor and blast the roof.
-你要怎么做到  -你來做
- Well, how are you going to do that? - You're going to do it.
去中央控制臺  打開所有電路
Go to the central console, open up all the circuits.
等我撤離了屋頂  就告訴你
When I get clear of the roof, I'll let you know.
你就按下主旁路按鈕
You're going to hit the master bypass button.
上面的一切都會被燒毀
It's going to fry everything up here.
好  我這就進去
Okay. I'm going in now.
一定等我離開屋頂的  我給你爭取點時間
Make sure you wait till I clear the roof. I'll buy you some time.
這個看上去挺重要
This looks important!
我一向不怎么喜歡這種玩意
I never had a taste for this sort of thing,
但我得承認  我非常喜歡這件戰衣
but I must admit, I'm deeply enjoying the suit!
你可算超常發揮了  托尼
You finally outdid yourself, Tony!
你會讓你父親自豪的
You'd have made your father proud!
準備好了  托尼  快離開屋頂
It's ready, Tony! Get off the roof!
托尼
Tony!
真是諷刺  托尼
How ironic, Tony!
你想讓世界上不再有武器
Trying to rid the world of weapons,
卻發明了最棒的武器
you gave it its best one ever!
-派珀  -現在
- Pepper! - And now
我要拿它殺了你
I'm going to kill you with it!
-你扯掉了我的瞄準系統  -按按鈕
- You ripped out my targeting system! - Time to hit the button!
-你叫我別按的  -別動  你個小混蛋
- You told me not to! - Hold still, you little prick!
-動手吧  -你會死的
- Just do it! - You'll die!
按吧
Push it!
托尼
Tony!
各位都拿到了昨晚斯塔克工業
You've all received the official statement of
詹姆斯·羅德中校  斯塔克工業事件
各位都拿到了昨晚斯塔克工業
You've all received the official statement of
事件經過的官方報告
what occurred at Stark lndustries last night.
詹姆斯·羅德中校  斯塔克工業事件
有未經證實的報告稱
There have been unconfirmed reports
詹姆斯·羅德中校  斯塔克工業事件
一件機器人原型機發生故障
that a robotic prototype malfunctioned
詹姆斯·羅德中校  斯塔克工業事件
導致方舟反應堆受損
and caused damage to the arc reactor.
詹姆斯·羅德中校  斯塔克工業事件
導致方舟反應堆受損
and caused damage to the arc reactor.
幸好  托尼·斯塔克的一位私人保鏢
Fortunately, a member of Tony Stark's personal security staff...
鋼鐵俠是誰
幸好  托尼·斯塔克的一位私人保鏢
Fortunately, a member of Tony Stark's personal security staff...
"鋼鐵俠"  挺上口  挺響亮的
"Iron Man." That's kind of catchy. It's got a nice ring to it.
鋼鐵俠是誰
"鋼鐵俠"  挺上口  挺響亮的
"Iron Man." That's kind of catchy. It's got a nice ring to it.
雖然并不準確
I mean, it's not technically accurate.
戰衣是金鈦合金
The suit's a gold-titanium alloy,
但這種意向呼之欲出
but it's kind of evocative, the imagery, anyway.
這是你的不在場證明
Here's your alibi.
好
Okay.
-你在你的游艇上  -嗯
- You were on your yacht. - Yeah.
我們有港口報告證明你整晚都在阿瓦隆
We have port papers that put you in Avalon all night,
還有你50位賓客的宣誓證詞
and sworn statements from 50 of your guests.
或許該說只有我和派珀
See, I was thinking maybe we should say it was just Pepper and me
單獨在島上
alone on the island.
-就是這樣的  -好吧
- That's what happened. - All right.
照讀就行
Just read it, word for word.
上面沒提斯坦尼
There's nothing about Stane here.
這已經處理好了  他去度假了
That's being handled. He's on vacation.
小型飛機的安全記錄很差
Small aircraft have such a poor safety record.
但關于保鏢的那套掩護說辭呢
But what about the whole cover story that it's a bodyguard?
他是我的...這...
He's my... I mean, is that...
這太站不住腳了吧
That's kind of flimsy, don't you think?
我不是第一次做這種事了  斯塔克先生
This isn't my first rodeo, Mr Stark.
按官方說辭念就行
Just stick to the official statement,
很快  這一切都會過去了
and soon, this will all be behind you.
你有90秒
You've got 90 seconds.
科爾森特工
Agent Coulson?
我想說  非常感謝你的一切幫助
I just wanted to say thank you very much for all of your help.
這是我們的職責  我們還會再聯系的
That's what we do. You'll be hearing from us.
-你們叫國土戰略  -喊我們神盾局就行
- From the Strategic Homeland... - Just call us S.H.I.E.L.D.
好
Right.
我們開始吧
Let's get this show on the road.
其實也沒那么糟
You know, it's actually not that bad.
就連我都不覺得自己像鋼鐵俠
Even I don't think I'm Iron Man.
-你不是鋼鐵俠  -我是
- You're not Iron Man. - Am so.
-你不是  -好吧  隨你
- You're not. - All right, suit yourself.
如果我是鋼鐵俠
You know, if I were Iron Man,
我會有個知道我真實身份的女友
I'd have this girlfriend who knew my true identity.
而且她會很崩潰
She'd be a wreck,
因為她會非常擔心我會不會送命
'cause she'd always be worrying that I was going to die,
但又為我的成就感到驕傲
yet so proud of the man I'd become.
她會非常矛盾  而這又讓她更加
She'd be wildly conflicted, which would only make her more
為我瘋狂了
crazy about me.
你難道就沒想過那晚的事嗎
Tell me you never think about that night.
-哪一晚  -你知道的
- What night? - You know.
你是說
Are you talking about
我們一起跳舞的那晚嗎
the night that we danced
然后我們上了屋頂
and went up on the roof,
然后
and then
你去樓下拿酒
you went downstairs to get me a drink,
然后就撇下了我一人
and you left me there, by myself?
你是說那晚嗎
Is that the night you're talking about?
我猜也是
Thought so.
沒有別的事了吧  斯塔克先生
Will that be all, Mr Stark?
是的  沒別的事了  波茨小姐
Yes, that will be all, Miss Potts.
現在  斯塔克先生準備了一份聲明
And now, Mr Stark has prepared a statement.
他不會接受提問的  謝謝
He will not be taking any questions. Thank you.
自我上次見大家過去好一陣了
Been a while since I was in front of you.
我這次還是照稿讀吧
I figure I'll stick to the cards this time.
有人猜測
There's been speculation
我卷入了之前發生在
that I was involved in the events that occurred
高速和屋頂上的事件
on the freeway and the rooftop...
抱歉  斯塔克先生
I'm sorry, Mr Stark,
你真的指望我們相信
but do you honestly expect us to believe that
那是一個穿戰衣的保鏢  碰巧出現
that was a bodyguard in a suit that conveniently appeared,
-盡管你...  -我知道情況讓人糊涂
- despite the fact that you... - I know that it's confusing.
質疑官方說辭是一回事
It is one thing to question the official story,
但提出瘋狂指控  或暗示說
and another thing entirely to make wild accusations,
我是個超級英雄可是另一碼事了
or insinuate that I'm a superhero.
我可沒說你是超級英雄
I never said you were a superhero.
是嗎  那很好
Didn't? Well, good,
因為那是不著邊際  異想天開的
because that would be outlandish and fantastic.
我顯然不是做英雄的料
I'm just not the hero type. Clearly.
我有一堆性格缺陷
With this laundry list of character defects,
犯過那么多錯誤
all the mistakes I've made,
-還很公開  -照稿讀就行
- largely public. - Just stick to the cards, man.
好  好
Yeah, okay. Yeah.
事實就是
The truth is
我就是鋼鐵俠
I am Iron Man.
賈維斯
Jarvis!
歡迎回家  先生
Welcome home, sir.
"我就是鋼鐵俠"
"I am Iron Man."
你以為你是這世上唯一的超級英雄嗎
You think you're the only superhero in the world?
斯塔克先生
Mr Stark,
你已經成為了更大的宇宙的一部分
you've become part of a bigger universe.
你只是現在還不知道
You just don't know it yet.
你是誰
Who the hell are you?
尼克·弗瑞  神盾局局長
Nick Fury, Director of S.H.I.E.L.D.
我來跟你談談復仇者聯盟
I'm here to talk to you about the Avenger Initiative.